Noel Phyllis Birkby Papers, 1932-1994
Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College
- SERIES VIII. FILMS AND VIDEOTAPES
  - Films
    - Art Films
      - Seashells By the Seashore (Box 63, Folder 64)
      - Shirley Walton (Box 63, Folder 65)
      - "Stamford" Long Island Beach (Box 63, Folder 66)
      - "Stamford" II 8/68 (Box 63, Folder 67)
      - "Stamford" (Box 63, Folder 67A)
      - "Sun on Water/Sky/Rough Cut(?)" Beach Sunset (Box 63, Folder 68)
      - "Tractor," 1971 (Box 63, Folder 69-70)
      - "Two Bridges" Brooklyn Bridge (Box 63, Folder 71)
      - Two Bridges Manhattan (Box 63, Folder 72)
      - "Two Bridges ______" Neighborhood/Manhattan Bridge, 1969 (Box 63, Folder 73)
      - Untitled (Box 63, Folder 74)
      - Washington Square Park, circa 1970, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 75-81)
      - Washington Square Park, circa 1970, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 82)
      - Washington Square Park, circa 1970, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 83)
      - Wholeo (Box 65, Folder 84)
      - Wind Chimes, 11/71 (Box 64, Folder 85)
      - Windsor (Box 64, Folder 86-87)
    - Personal
      - "Amazon Weekend" (Box 64, Folder 88)
      - "Amazon Weekend" (Box 64, Folder 89)
      - CR Volleyball (Box 64, Folder 90-91)
      - CR #1 Dinner Party at Kate Millett's Farm (Box 64, Folder 92)
      - "Dance" Birthday Party (Box 64, Folder 93)
      - "Dykes at Jill's Weekend" Upstate NY (Box 66, Folder 94)
      - Esther, Louise, Roberta, Martha, Aug 1971 (Box 64, Folder 95)
      - Friendship Circle at Beach House, 1972 (Box 64, Folder 96-97)
      - The Girl Gang (Box 64, Folder 98)
      - "Group" (Box 64, Folder 99)
      - Group (Box 64, Folder 100)
      - "Jane and Jill" (Box 64, Folder 101)
      - Jane O'Wyatt and Jill Johnston (Box 64, Folder 102)
      - Jennifer's Birthday Party, 6/67 (Box 64, Folder 103)
      - Jill Johnston and Van, 3/72 (Box 64, Folder 104)
      - Maryland II (Box 64, Folder 105)
      - Old Peekskill Calendar, 1976 (Box 64, Folder 106)
      - "Peekskill--Leslie/Dinah" (Box 66, Folder 107)
      - "Pt. Pleasant," 12/67 (Box 66, Folder 108)
      - R, K, W, Cats (Box 66, Folder 109)
      - Self Portrait: Hello, Hello, Hello (Box 66, Folder 110)
      - "Softball" (Box 66, Folder 111)
      - Street Fair (Box 66, Folder 112)
      - Tower, Esther, Louise (Box 66, Folder 113)
      - "Woodstock Pool/Dana's Baseball Team" (Box 66, Folder 114)
    - Political
      - "Abortion St. Pat's" Protest (Box 66, Folder 115)
      - "Abortion" Rights, St. Patrick's Protest, reel #2 (Box 66, Folder 116)
      - Albany March (Box 66, Folder 117)
      - "April 10" Demonstration in Washington DC (Box 66, Folder 118)
      - "Dec 12 Demo" Women's Liberation Demonstration 1970 (Box 66, Folder 119)
      - "5th St." (Box 67, Folder 120)
      - "First 1/2 of March '71?" Women's March, first half, '71? (Box 67, Folder 121)
      - Gay March 7/71 (Box 67, Folder 122)
      - Gay March, 1977 [?] (Box 67, Folder 122A-B)
      - "It's All Right to Be Woman Theater" (Box 67, Folder 123-126)
      - "Patchapines, E-Day, 42nd St., Peace March"Demo/42nd St./Patchapines Yoga Hour (Box 67, Folder 127)
      - Women's Lib March A (Box 67, Folder 128)
      - "Women's Liberation March Trial Blowups" B (Box 67, Folder 129)
      - Women's Lib 26 Aug 1970 (Box 67, Folder 130)
      - Women's Strike for Peace and Equality (Box 67, Folder 131)
      - Untitled (Box 67, Folder 132)
    - Travel
      - "Bahamas" (Box 68, Folder 133)
      - "Canyon de Chelly" [formerly Soleri Cement A] (Box 68, Folder 134)
      - "Maryland" (Box 68, Folder 135)
      - "Maryland" (Box 68, Folder 136)
      - Miscellaneous Road Footage A-G (Box 68, Folder 137-143)
      - Olympics, Out of Focus Field Hockey, 1984 (Box 68, Folder 144-147)
      - "Patchapines" (Box 68, Folder 148)
      - "Saigon," 1973 (Box 68, Folder 149)
      - Saigon [?], 1973 [?] (Box 68, Folder 150)
  - Videotapes
    - Preservation masters--VHS format
      [Closed. Use copies must be made for research use].
      - Kay Standley and Bradley Soule lecture on perceptions of discrimination in the professions and forecast for change for women professionals and the professions in general, 13 Dec 1972 at the Institute for Architecture and Urban Studies, New York, NY (Box 69, Folder 1-2)
      - Alliance of Women in Architecture
        - Discussion of history, goals and activities of the AWA at the Architectural League of New York, n.d. (Box 69, Folder 3)
        - General meeting, 10 Aug [1972] (Box 69, Folder 3a-3b)
        - AWA members' discussion of AWA's relationship with UIFA, 26 Oct 1972 (Box 69, Folder 4)
        - Consciousness raising
          - Introduction to CR: AWA group discussing CR at Architectural League of NY (Box 69, Folder 5)
          - CR session with AWA members at Judy Klein's, [1972] (Box 69, Folder 6-7)
        - Architect Judy Edelman interviewed by Sarah Brezavar, n.d. (Box 69, Folder 8)
        - Union Internationale des Femmes Architectes, 3rd Annual Congress, Bucharest, 1972: interviews with women architects, an engineer, and the president of UIFA (Box 69, Folder 9-10)
        - Architectural Barriers to women: mothers with young children, c. 1972 (Box 69, Folder 11)
      - Video document of Women in Architecture Symposium, Washington University, St. Louis, March 1974 (Box 69, Folder 12)
      - "Mardelle [Shepley]" Discussion at Columbia University(?) the status of women in Architecture followed by footage of women making architectural drawings and models, n.d. (Box 69, Folder 13)
    - VHS Originals
      - Lesbian Activists at Mid-Life, meeting 29 Jan 1989 (Box 69, Folder 14-15)
      - Group at 51 Castle St., Great Barrington, 25 Nov 1990 (Box 69, Folder 16)
      - "NYIT 90--New Mexico/Pow Wow" (Box 69, Folder 17)
      - Noel Phyllis Birkby Memorial/Party, Kate Millett's loft, 295 Bowery, NYC, 5 Jun 1994 (Box 69, Folder 18)
      - "Birkby's Greatest Hits" video of still photographs of/by NPB shown at Memorial/Party, 5 Jun 1994 (Box 70, Folder 19)
      - "In Memoriam: Phyllis Birkby" short film by Barbara Hammer shown at Memorial/Party, 5 Jun 1994 (2 copies) (Box 70, Folder 20)
      - Group (Sidney Abbott, Barbara Love, Alma Routsong, etc.), Horse Show, n.d. (Box 70, Folder 21)
      - "Dr. Ji" Tai Chi, n.d. (Box 70, Folder 22)
      - "Cats, Fire Dept., Horse Show," n.d. (Box 70, Folder 23)
    - Film Transfers, VHS format--Preservation Masters
      - "CR Volleyball" (2 copies) (Box 70, Folder 24)
      - Six Short Films by NPB ("Head Change," "Tractor," "Kite," "5th St.," "Windsor," and "Amazon Weekend") (Box 70, Folder 25)
      - Transfer of films 94-102, 104-105, 107, 110-113 to VHS (Box 70, Folder 26)
      - Transfer of films 115-119, 121 to VHS (Box 70, Folder 27)
      - Transfer of films 122-129, 131-132 to VHS (Box 70, Folder 28)
    - Original Videotapes, reel-to-reel format (Box 71, Folder 1-13)
    - Restoration Masters, U-Matic format (Box 72, Folder 1-13)
  - In-house Use Copies, Transfers of Films
    - #90-91, VHS (Box 72a)
    - #7, 7A, 8, 20, 18, 23, 22, 30, 31, 62, 71-73 DVD (Box 72a)
    - #75-83 DVD (Box 72a)
    - #40, 54-56, 69-70, 86-89, 120 [transferred from VHS 25] DVD (Box 72a)
    - #94-102, 104-105, 107, 110-113 [transferred from VHS 26] DVD (Box 72a)
    - #27, 115-119, 121 [transferred from VHS 27] DVD (Box 72a)
    - #122, 122A, 122B, 123-129, 132 [transferred from VHS 28] DVD (Box 72a)
    - #130 [transferred from VHS 28a] DVD (Box 72a)
- SERIES IX. TAPE RECORDINGS
  - Cassettes: Preservation Copies
    Preservation master copies: DO NOT USE [see box 81a for use copies]
    - Personal
      - Audio letter, Bertha Harris to NPB, n.d. (Box 73, Folder 1)
      - Audio letter, NPB to Bertha Harris, n.d. (Box 73, Folder 2)
      - Consciousness raising group, "Butch/Femme," 1 Oct 1971 (Box 73, Folder 3)
      - Side A: Consciousness raising group, "Butch/Femme," 1 Oct 1971 (cont'd) Side B: music for Tractor film and Washington Square Park sounds (Box 73, Folder 4)
      - Consciousness raising group, "Bisexuality," 9? Oct [1971] (Box 73, Folder 5)
      - Side A: Consciousness raising group, "Bisexuality," 9? Oct [1971] (cont'd) Side B: "Sandy # 1," 14 Aug 1971 (Box 73, Folder 6)
      - Consciousness raising group, "Straight," 2 Jan 197[2] (Box 73, Folder 7)
      - Jill Johnston reading from her work for NPB, n.d. (Box 73, Folder 8)
      - "Mod Drama," performance, Bici [Forbes]/Mallory [Millett Danaher], n.d. (Box 73, Folder 9)
      - "On the Streets of Sagaris," performance, Emily Medvec recorded by Hera, 1975 (Box 73, Folder 10)
      - Psychic reading with Michael Hughes, n.d. (Box 73, Folder 11)
    - Therapy Session Tapes
      THERAPY SESSION TAPES RESTRICTED UNTIL 1 JAN 2033
      - Therapy session with Beverly Dennis, 7 Mar 1978 (Box 73, Folder 12)
      - Therapy session with Beverly Dennis, 30 Jul [1978] (Box 73, Folder 13)
      - Therapy session with Beverly Dennis, n.d. (Box 73, Folder 14)
      - Side A: Therapy session with Beverly Dennis, n.d. Side B: "Jany V. S." interview re windmill, n.d. (Box 73, Folder 15)
      - Therapy session, n.d. "Phyllis" (2 cassettes) (Box 73, Folder 16-17)
      - Therapy session, n.d. "Session" (3 cassettes) (Box 73, Folder 18-20)
      - Side A: Therapy session, n.d. "ice cubes" Side B: Vietnamese Music (Box 73, Folder 21)
    - Political
      - Women's Liberation March, 26 Aug 1970 (Box 74, Folder 22)
      - Women's March on City Hall, 12 Dec 1970 (Box 74, Folder 23)
      - Women's Liberation March, Aug 1971 (2 cassettes) (Box 74, Folder 24-25)
      - Women's March, 1972/ Discussion at Jill's re ritual, matriarchy (Box 74, Folder 26)
      - speech, Betty Friedan, IDCA, 1975 (Box 74, Folder 27)
      - Women's National March on the Pentagon, 10 Apr 1971 (Box 74, Folder 28)
      - Kate Millett interviews, 1/5/77 and 12/4/7[7] (2 cassettes) (Box 74, Folder 29-30)
      - Christopher Street March/Rally, 1977? (3 cassettes) (Box 74, Folder 31-33)
      - National Women's Conference, Houston, TX, 18-21 Nov 1977 (3 cassettes) (Box 74, Folder 34-36)
      - Presentation at conference [MLA 1974?] re lesbian literature, n.d. (Box 74, Folder 37)
      - Feminist Perspectives on Pornography conference, San Francisco, CA, 17-19 Nov 1978 (3 cassettes) (Box 74, Folder 38-40)
      - Kate Millett interview [not by NPB], n.d. (Box 74, Folder 41)
      - Interview re welfare, Mary Vogel [not by NPB], n.d. (Box 74, Folder 42)
    - Architecture
      - Expo 68 Whole Life Expo, San Francisco, Apr 1987: panel, "Housing for Everyone" Boyd, Herman, McMahaon, et al. (Box 75, Folder 43)
      - Magrit Kennedy, talk, "Energy," Oslo, Norway, 1982 (Box 75, Folder 44)
      - Magrit Kennedy talk on women and architecture, n.d. (Box 75, Folder 45)
      - Monterey Design Conference, Apr 1987, "Human Nature and Architecture" (Box 75, Folder 46)
      - Two Bridges Neighborhood Council meeting(?), n.d. (Box 75, Folder 47)
      - Translation by Jan D. of articles re architecture and women from German periodicals, n.d. (Box 75, Folder 48)
    - Films
      - Second Wave of Feminism
        - Interview, June Arnold, 7 Jun 1977 (Box 75, Folder 49)
        - Interview, Esther Newton and Kathryn McHargue, n.d. (2 cassettes) second tape b/w Discussion among friends (Box 75, Folder 50-51)
        - Interview, Sue Perlgut, 10 Jun 1977 (Box 75, Folder 52)
      - General
        - Washington Square Park: sounds, interview, n.d. (Box 75, Folder 53)
          [see also CR tape]
        - Discussion at Kate Millett's farm about progress on a film, n.d. (Box 75, Folder 54)
        - "Tractor" soundtrack, [see CR tape] (Box 75, Folder 4)
        - "Mooncircles" slide lecture soundtrack for "fan slides", n.d. (Box 75, Folder 55)
    - Research, Speaking, Writing
      - Elderly Housing
        - "Old People Pratt Tape," n.d. (Box 75, Folder 56)
        - Community ___________ Society meeting re elderly, Oct 1975 (Box 75, Folder 57)
        - Dover(?) St. meeting re elderly, n.d. (Box 75, Folder 58)
        - Discussion, "Kids/Old People," n.d. (Box 75, Folder 59)
      - Women and the Built Environment
        - Environmental Fantasy Discussions
          - "Washington women, Val, Jo," 31 Jul 1974 (Box 75, Folder 60)
          - "Val, Jo, L.," 4 Aug [1974?] (Box 75, Folder 61)
          - "Dinah's Fantasy childhood," 25 Aug [1974?] (Box 75, Folder 62)
          - Interview, Liza ?, Cheryl ?, and Mary ?, and NPB, Mar 1974 (Box 75, Folder 63)
            [see also Research, Speaking, and Writing "Amazon Architecture"]
          - "Tape on fantasy, cont'd," 9 Sep 1974 (Box 76, Folder 64)
          - Ann Pollon, Gail ?, Bertha Harris, n.d. (Box 76, Folder 65)
          - Side A: Ann Pollon, Gail?, Bertha Harris, n.d. Side B: "Goddard" slide lecture, n.d. (Box 76, Folder 66)
          - Julia ? and Sahli [Cavallaro?], n.d. Lectures/workshops/conference presentations (Box 76, Folder 67)
          - University of Detroit slide lecture, "Women in Architecture,"10 Oct 1974 (Box 76, Folder 68)
          - Gay Academic Union Conference, New York University, 30 Nov 1974, "Negotiating Space: The Woman-Built Environment (Box 76, Folder 69)
          - Workshop, NPB and LKW, "Women in Design: The Next Decade" conference, Women's Building, Los Angeles, CA, 20-21 Mar 1975 (Box 76, Folder 70)
          - Lecture and workshop, "Two Feminist Designers, Leslie Kanes Weisman and Noel Phyllis Birkby," University of Wisconsin--Green Bay, 1-2 May 1975 (Box 76, Folder 71-72)
          - Workshop, "Fantasies and Realities: Women's Visions of the Built Environment," Feminist Visions of the Future conference, California State, Chico, CA, Mar 1979 (Box 76, Folder 73)
          - Workshop led by NPB, unidentified, n.d. (Box 76, Folder 74)
          - Workshop led by NPB and LKW, unidentified, n.d. (Box 76, Folder 75)
        - Women's Vernacular Architecture
          - Interviews, Virginia Gray, Santa Fe, NM, 11 Apr 1979; Laurie Davis (Hogan dwelling), n.d. (Box 76, Folder 76)
          - Interviews, Santa Fe, NM, n.d. (Box 76, Folder 77)
          - Interviews, Laurie Davis, Nancy Lipsett, Santa Fe, NM, n.d. (Box 76, Folder 78)
          - Interviews, Tipi Village, Isla Vista, CA, Mona and Jade, n.d. (2 cassettes) (Box 76, Folder 79-80)
          - Interviews in Santa Barbara, Sandy? Pat? (Box 76, Folder 81)
          - Interview, Pyramid of Amaratasu, Jenner, CA, n.d. (Box 76, Folder 82)
          - Interview, Joyce Johnston, Truro, MA, n.d. (Box 76, Folder 83)
          - Interview, Tye Farm, H. Bye, n.d. (Box 76, Folder 84)
          - Interview, Marsha Oliver (oval house), n.d. (Box 77, Folder 85)
          - Interview, Lorie ?, n.d. (Box 77, Folder 86)
          - Interview, Shannon's cabin n.d., Fantasy Workshop, Therapy session with Beverly Dennis, [Aug 1978] (Box 77, Folder 87)
        - Reference
          - Leslie Kanes Weisman teaching ARIII class [University of Detroit?], 5 Sep 1974 (Box 77, Folder 88)
          - Talk by Ena Dubnoff, "How space has beenappropriated by women to satisfy their material and creative needs," Long Beach, 1985 (Box 77, Folder 89)
          - Slide lecture on women and design by Sheila de Bretteville, n.d. (Box 77, Folder 90)
          - Women's Development Corporation meeting, n.d. (Box 77, Folder 91)
    - Teaching
      - City College of the City University of New York, architecture class, n.d. (Box 77, Folder 92)
      - [Pratt Institute?], Basic Design Class, 20 Oct 1974 (Box 77, Folder 93)
      - Womanschool Adult Education Center, Women and the Built Environment, Oct 1975 (2 cassettes) (Box 77, Folder 94-95)
      - Gay Academic Union Conference, panel "The Lesbian Experience in Education," (Box 77, Folder 96)
  - Cassettes: Originals (Box 78-81)
    DO NOT USE Original cassette tapes [see box 81a for use copies]
  - Cassettes: Use Copies
    - Consciousness raising group, "Butch/Femme," 1 Oct 1971 [2 compact discs] (Box 81a, Folder 3)
    - Side A: Consciousness raising group, "Butch/Femme," 1 Oct 1971 (cont'd) and Side B: music for Tractor film and Washington Square Park sounds [cassette] (Box 81a, Folder 4)
    - Consciousness raising group, "Bisexuality," 9? Oct [1971] [cassette] (Box 81a, Folder 5)
    - Side A: Consciousness raising group, "Bisexuality," 9? Oct [1971] (cont'd) and Side B: "Sandy # 1," 14 Aug 1971 [cassette] (Box 81a, Folder 6)
    - Consciousness raising group, "Straight," 2 Jan 197[2] [cassette] (Box 81a, Folder 7)
  - Reel-to-Reel
    Originals: DO NOT USE
    - Personal
      - Audio letter, Barbara Hammer to NPB, "A Tape #1," 28-31, Jul 1978 (Box 82, Folder 1)
        RESTRICTED UNTIL 1 JAN 2038
    - Films
      - Second Wave of Feminism
        - Kate Millett talk at Gay Academic Union conference, University of Southern California, 25 Nov 1978 (Box 82, Folder 2)
        - Women's Liberation March, 1970 (Box 82, Folder 3)
        - Interview: Shirley Walton, 12 Jun and 31 July 1977 (Box 82, Folder 4-5)
        - Interview: Charlotte Bunch, n.d. (Box 82, Folder 6)
        - Interview: June Arnold, 7 Jun 1977 (Box 82, Folder 7)
        - Robin Morgan Yarrow-Birkby broadcast on Velvet Sledgehammer 31 Jul 1977 (2 tapes) (Box 82, Folder 8-9)
      - Second Wave of Feminism, interview: Robin Morgan, n.d. Washington Square Park, sounds, n.d. (Box 82, Folder 10)
      - Second Wave of Feminism, interview: Dinah Utah andNancy Johnson, 13 Jun 1977 (Box 83, Folder 11)
      - Second Wave of Feminism, interview: Carole Rosenthal, n.d. Washington Square Park, sounds, n.d. (Box 83, Folder 12)
    - Research, Speaking, and Writing
      - Women and the Built Environment
        - Lecture "Feminism and Architecture in the U.S.," Sarah Kulturzentrum/Cafe fur Frauen, Stuttgart, Germany, 29 Aug 1980 (Box 83, Folder 13)
        - Workshop with LKW, n.d. (Box 83, Folder 14)
        - Interview at Pyramid of Amaratasu, Barbara [Hammer], Claire, Alicia?, NPB, Feb 1978 (Box 83, Folder 15)
- OVERSIZE MATERIALS
  - Series I. Biographical and Financial Material
    - General (Box 84, Folder 791)
    - Artwork by NPB and friends (Box 84, Folder 792)
    - Education: Yale University portfolio and Third Year Design problems and class work (Box 84, Folder 793)
    - Sketchbooks (Box 85, Folder 794)
    - Travel (Box 85, Folder 795)
  - Series II. Correspondence
    - Correspondence (Box 86, Folder 796)
  - Series III. Architecture
    - Licenses (Box 86, Folder 797)
    - Projects
      - Bellevue Environs (Box 86, Folder 798)
      - Campbell (Box 86, Folder 799)
      - Dominguez (Box 86, Folder 800)
      - Knowlton (Box 86, Folder 801)
      - Long Island University (Box 86, Folder 802)
      - Pollon (Box 86, Folder 803)
      - Watering Place (Box 87, Folder 804)
      - Waterside Houses (Box 87, Folder 805)
      - Women's Liberation Center (Box 87, Folder 806)
      - unidentified (Box 87, Folder 807)
    - Subject Files
      - General (Box 87, Folder 808)
      - Alternative Construction Systems (Box 87, Folder 809)
  - Series IV. Research, Speaking and Writing
    - General (Box 88, Folder 810)
    - Women and the Built Environment: Fantasy Drawings (Box 88, Folder 811)
  - Series VI. Subject Files
    - Individuals (Box 88, Folder 812)
    - Women, A - F (Box 88, Folder 813)
    - Women, G - Z (Box 88, Folder 814)
    - Homosexuality (Box 88, Folder 815)
  - Series VII. Photographs
    - Personal (Box 89, Folder 816)
    - Architecture (Box 89, Folder 817)
    - Artistic (Box 89, Folder 818)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 89, Folder 819)
    - Political (Box 89, Folder 820)
    - Travel (Box 89, Folder 821)
- OVERSIZE MATERIALS -- TUBES
  - Series I. Biographical and Financial Material
    - Education: Cooper Union student drawings (Box Tube 1)
  - Series III. Architecture
    - Projects: Long Island University Library/Learning Center (Box Tube 2)
    - Projects: Waterside Houses (Box Tube 3)
  - Series IV. Research, Speaking, and Writing
    - Women and the Built Environment: Environmental Fantasy Drawings
      - "Aug 13 WSPA" (Box Tube 4)
      - "L.A. Conference" (Box Tube 5)
      - Unidentified (Box Tubes 6-14)
- OVERSIZE -- FLAT FILE
  - Series I. Biographical and Financial Material
    - Artwork by NPB and friends (Map-case Dr. 8, Folder 52)
    - Education, student work
      - Miscellaneous student projects (2 folders) (Map-case Dr. 8, Folder 53-54)
      - Medical Building (Map-case Dr. 8, Folder 55)
      - Cooper Union
        - Miscellaneous (Map-case Dr. 8, Folder 56)
        - Urban Row House (Map-case Dr. 8, Folder 57)
        - Episcopal Church (Map-case Dr. 8, Folder 58)
        - Group Medical Center (Map-case Dr. 8, Folder 59)
        - International University, NY campus w/Lynda Simmons (Map-case Dr. 8, Folder 60)
      - Yale University
        - Thesis: Hofstra University Gymnasium (Map-case Dr. 8, Folder 61)
        - Housing for the Elderly (Map-case Dr. 8, Folder 62)
        - Museum (Map-case Dr. 8, Folder 63)
        - Recital Hall (Map-case Dr. 8, Folder 64)
  - Series IV. Research, Speaking, and Writing
    - General (Map-case Dr. 9, Folder 65)
    - Women and the Built Environment: Women's Vernacular Architecture, M.F. Beal house plan (Map-case Dr. 9, Folder 66)
    - Women and the Built Environment: Fantasy Drawings (Map-case Dr. 9, Folder 67-69)
  - Series III. Architecture
    - Subject Files (Map-case Dr. 10, Folder 70)
  - Series V. Teaching
    - Teaching (Map-case Dr. 10, Folder 71)
  - Series VI: Subject Files
    - Individuals (Map-case Dr. 10, Folder 72)
    - Women: Artists (Map-case Dr. 10, Folder 73)
    - Women's Organizations, The Woman's Building (Map-case Dr. 10, Folder 74)
    - Homosexuality (Map-case Dr. 10, Folder 75)